certify.com 2019-12-18

# Privacy Policy - Certify

**Privacy Statement**  
Last Updated: **5/18/2018**   
Certify, Inc. ("Certify") is the developer of certain web based software products and services. With all of Certify’s products and services, Certify adheres to this Privacy Policy. Certify realizes how important the privacy and security of personal information is to its users. Certify’s Privacy Policy applies to all of its users automatically. Certify works very hard to maintain the confidentiality of all data that is submitted to it. The use of information collected through the Certify service is limited to the purpose of providing the service for which you have engaged Certify.

**EU-U.S. Privacy Shield**  
Certify participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework.  We are committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries and Switzerland, respectively, in reliance on each Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles.  To learn more about the Privacy Shield Frameworks, and to view our certification, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List.  
[[https://www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/)]

Certify is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under each Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf.  Certify complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU and Switzerland, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Frameworks, Certify is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, Certify may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

**Dispute Resolution**  
If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that Certify has not addressed satisfactorily, please contact Certify’s U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website [<https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint>], you may be entitled to invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

**Information we collect**  
In order to provide its services, Certify collects various types of information, including personal information, about its users. When you sign up for a Certify account, you will be asked to provide basic registration information, such as user name, password, email address and SMS number. In some cases we require billing information, such as credit card information. Billing information is encrypted at all times and is stored on secure servers. 

Certify collects information under the direction of its clients, and has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. If you are a user with one of our clients and would no longer like to be contacted by the client regarding the use of Certify service, please contact the client directly regarding the issue. 

**Transfer of Information**  
Certify may transfer personal information to companies that helps it provide the service. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the Certify Terms of Use Agreements entered into between Certify and its clients.

**Tracking Technologies**  
Certify and its partners use cookies or similar technologies to analyze trends, administer the website, track users' movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about its user base as a whole. You can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level, but if you choose to disable cookies, it may limit your use of certain features or functions on our website or service.

Certify uses the mobile analytics software to allow it to better understand the functionality of its Mobile Software on your phone. This software may record information such as how often you use the application, the events that occur within the application, aggregated usage, performance data, and where the application was downloaded from. Certify does not link the information it stores within the analytics software to any personally identifiable information you submit within the mobile application.

**Online Advertising & Remarketing**  
In order to reach people, like you who have previously visited Certify’s website and shown interest in its services, Certify uses Google’s AdWords "remarketing" service. This service allows Certify’s ads to be shown to you as you travel across the internet, by placing a cookie on your web browser. All it does is, it says, this person visited this page, so show them ads relating to that page. Using a cookie for remarketing purposes only allows Certify to tailor its marketing programs to better suit your needs by only displaying ads that are relevant to you. However, you are free to opt of Google’s use of cookies by visiting [Google’s Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/ads/preferences) web page.

Certify partners with a third party to display advertising on its website or to manage its advertising on other sites. Certify’s third party partner may use cookies or similar technologies in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to opt out of interest-based advertising, click [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) [or if located in the European Union click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)]. Please note you may continue to receive generic ads. 

**Log Information**  
While using the Certify website or a Certify service, Certify servers automatically record information that your browser sends. These logs may include information such as login and logout times, your web request, IP address, browser type, browser language, mobile device type, operating system, the date and time of your request and one or more cookies that may uniquely identify you. 

**Communications**  
When you communicate with other users or Certify’s staff through the Certify website or via a Certify service, those communications are saved in order to process your inquiries, respond to your requests and improve Certify services. 

You may sign-up to receive communications from Certify, including any online or physical forms of communication. If you would like to discontinue receiving this information, you may update your email preferences by using the “Unsubscribe” or "Update Subscription Preferences" links found in emails Certify sends to you or at your member profile on Certify’s website or by contacting Certify at privacy@certify.com.

**Business Partners**  
Certify offers some of the services in connection with business partners. In some cases, information you provide under your Certify account may be shared with our business partners to provide services requested by you. Certify processes your information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

Certify uses third parties, such as GoToWebinar, to process registration and/or host and provide technical support for Certify webinars. If you register for and/or download or view a Certify webinar, Certify may provide your Information (including Personally Identifying Information) to these third parties to facilitate registration and access to the webinar. In addition, as discussed below, Certify (or its third party registration service) may provide your Information (including Personally Identifying Information) to companies that sponsor or underwrite portions of a webinar that you register for, download, or view.

Although Certify chooses its business partners carefully, it cannot be responsible for the privacy practices of websites operated by third parties that are linked to or from Certify’s website. Once you have left Certify’s website, you should be sure to check the applicable privacy statement of the third party website to determine how they will use information they collect from you.

**Protecting Your Data**  
Every precaution is taken to insure the security of your data while using the Certify website or a Certify service. Certify uses industry-standard firewalls, secure web servers (https), data encryption and authentication procedures, among other techniques, to maintain the security of your data and your online session.

**Using the Information**  
Certify uses personal information only for the purposes for which it was collected and in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Certify takes reasonable steps to ensure that the personal information it processes is accurate, complete, and current, but Certify depends on its users to update or correct their personal information whenever necessary.

Certify may use the information you provide about yourself to fulfill your requests for Certify products, programs, and services, to respond to your inquiries about Certify services, and to offer you other products, programs or services that Certify believes may be of interest to you.

Certify may use your personal information to create anonymous data records or aggregations of data, to perform statistical analyses and for other purposes, by removing information that makes the data personally identifiable to you.

Certify may use or disclose your information to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process, or to establish or exercise its legal rights or defend against legal claims.

If Certify believes it is necessary, it shall share your information in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person or the security of Certify network or services, violations of Certify’s Terms of Use Agreement, or as otherwise required by law.

If Certify is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website, of any change in ownership, uses of your personal information, and choices you may have regarding your personal information. We may also disclose your personal information to any other third party with your prior consent.

**Data Ownership**  
Any data you submit while using the Certify website or a Certify service belongs to you. You may remove it at any time. If you ask Certify to delete your account, Certify shall make commercially reasonable efforts to remove all of your data from its servers. Despite such removal efforts, portions of your data may remain on Certify’s production and back-up servers indefinitely.

Any information you submit that can identify you personally on a blog, bulletin board or chat room through the Certify website or a Certify service can be viewed and used by other Certify users, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. Certify is not responsible for your disclosure of this information in these forums.

**Access**  
Upon request Certify will provide you with information about whether or not Certify holds any of your personal information. You may access, correct, or request deletion of your personal information by logging in to your account, contacting your Certify Account Manager, or by contacting us at support@certify.com. Certify will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe.

Certify acknowledges that you have the right to access your personal information. Certify has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data should direct their query to the Certify’s client (the data controller). If requested to remove data we will respond within a reasonable timeframe.

In certain circumstances Certify may be required by law to retain your personal information, or may need to retain your personal information in order to continue providing a service.

**Policy Changes**  
Certify reserves the right at its sole discretion to make changes to this Privacy Policy at any time. You may review updates to Certify’s Terms of Use Agreement and/or Privacy Policy at any time via links on Certify’s website. You agree to accept electronic communications and/or postings of any revised Terms of Use Agreement and/or Privacy Policy on the Certify website, and you agree that such electronic communications or postings constitute notice to you of the revisions to the Terms of Use Agreement and/or Privacy Policy, as applicable. If Certify makes any material changes we shall notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this website prior to the change becoming effective.

**Questions?**  
If you have any questions or concerns about our collection, use, or disclosure of your information, please email us at [info@certify.com](mailto:info@certify.com) or contact us at 20 York Street, Portland ME 04101.  
Certify, Inc.
